# Oliver Bell

## https://ollie.codes

A knowledgeable, passionate, British computer programmer, with a First Class BSc (Hons) in Computer Science from Coventry University. Expertise in design, development, and deployment of high availability, microservice, tested, full-stack software. With vast experience working in software teams, gained from work in both in the UK and abroad.

# **Employment**

# YOOX Net-a-Porter Group, London, UK

Full Time Associate Software Developer (May 2019 - Present)

- JavaScript/TypeScript full-stack development for the Visual Merchandising team
- · GraphQL used exclusively for our app stack communication
- Pushed for and implemented a monorepo based architecture for the team
- Pushed for and helped implement Component Driven Development in React Storybook.

## Alelion Energy Systems GmbH, Pullach, Germany

Full Time **Software Engineering Internship** (August 2017 - September 2018)

- Developed HA software for their distributed energy storage platform
- Worked with Docker, Python, TypeScript, C++, and Java
- Wrote their main time-series API which used Scylla (cassandra) for a data backend
- Designed and wrote an orchestrator for dynamic service deployment to a docker swarm
- · Worked as lead in a small team to re-write their main "Control-Center" UI
- · Designed and implemented many microservices to split-up their UI backend

#### IndiCater Software LTD, Henley-On-Thames, UK

Full Time Intern Software Developer (July 2014 - August 2014) (July 2015 - September 2015)

- Developed web-based software used for the management of back-of-house catering
- Wrote server-side VBscript, and frontend javascript
- Took over development and maintenance of their undocumented customer support site

### **Tech**



### **Interests**

- Programming
- FPV Miniquad Racing
- Reverse engineering
- Free Software
- DevOps
- Skiing
- Film-making
- Electronics

## Other skills

- UK Driving license
- A2.2 German

## Part-time

- McDonalds (2013-2017)
- Compass (2016-2017)

## **Websites**

https://hqhero.com https://beefboard.mooo.com

## **Education**

First class BSc (Hons) Computer Science - Coventry University (2015-2019)

A Levels and GCSEs - Edgbarrow School, Crowthorne (2008-2015)

- Computing A Level (B) & GCSE (A)
- Maths A Level (C) & GCSE (A\*)

# **Projects**

#### **Embedded Android Headunit**

During my late teens I spent the majority of my free time developing custom software and hardware to embed a Nexus 7 tablet into the dashboard of my car. The focus of the project was reliability, which ended up being very hard to perfect. I have open-sourced all of the software I wrote to complete the headunit, available on my github.

## Online game injection

At age 16, I was at the forefront of reverse engineering a children's online game called Toontown. The client was written in python so, even though we couldn't read the sourcecode, arbitrary python code could be injected and executed in the game.

